<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Craigslist Spam Buttons updated &#8211; version 1.3	</title>
	<atom:link href="/craigslist-spam-buttons-v13/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/craigslist-spam-buttons-v13/</link>
	<description>Web development notes and commentary from Ryan Stille</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2012 08:06:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Richard		</title>
		<link>/craigslist-spam-buttons-v13/comment-page-2/#comment-2714</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2012 08:06:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=136#comment-2714</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What software do i need  for i-mac ???]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What software do i need  for i-mac ???</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Richard		</title>
		<link>/craigslist-spam-buttons-v13/comment-page-1/#comment-2713</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2012 08:05:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=136#comment-2713</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello, need help to stop craigslist spammers !!! I have a i-mac and really need help with these crooks ! Please help in anyway .
   




thx]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello, need help to stop craigslist spammers !!! I have a i-mac and really need help with these crooks ! Please help in anyway .</p>
<p>thx</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Steevo		</title>
		<link>/craigslist-spam-buttons-v13/comment-page-1/#comment-2410</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steevo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 20:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=136#comment-2410</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With the reloaded script the clpics doesn&amp;apos;t seem to work at all.&#160;&#160;Hmm. 
Now this is getting interesting.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With the reloaded script the clpics doesn&apos;t seem to work at all.&nbsp;&nbsp;Hmm.<br />
Now this is getting interesting.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Steevo		</title>
		<link>/craigslist-spam-buttons-v13/comment-page-1/#comment-2409</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steevo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 20:04:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=136#comment-2409</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, I reloaded it from the userscrips site, the stalling is resolved.&#160;&#160;Something crept in.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, I reloaded it from the userscrips site, the stalling is resolved.&nbsp;&nbsp;Something crept in.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Steevo		</title>
		<link>/craigslist-spam-buttons-v13/comment-page-1/#comment-2408</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steevo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 19:57:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=136#comment-2408</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&amp;apos;s actually worse than that, as far as I can tell the pics addon causes multiple other problems. 

One thing I did notice is even with the clpics disabled now, I notice if I click the spam button the script starts, the flagging box appears and stalls, and then the cl ad opens.&#160;&#160;

I click back to the list and the flagging box is still there.&#160;&#160;So not completing.&#160;&#160;

I just updated to the latest Firefox 3.6.18, but the problem remains. Even with the clpics disabled. 

I have to say the script that you and Steve worked on is by far the strongest solution to it&amp;apos;s problem.&#160;&#160;Sad to have it become broken.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&apos;s actually worse than that, as far as I can tell the pics addon causes multiple other problems. </p>
<p>One thing I did notice is even with the clpics disabled now, I notice if I click the spam button the script starts, the flagging box appears and stalls, and then the cl ad opens.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>I click back to the list and the flagging box is still there.&nbsp;&nbsp;So not completing.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>I just updated to the latest Firefox 3.6.18, but the problem remains. Even with the clpics disabled. </p>
<p>I have to say the script that you and Steve worked on is by far the strongest solution to it&apos;s problem.&nbsp;&nbsp;Sad to have it become broken.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Ryan		</title>
		<link>/craigslist-spam-buttons-v13/comment-page-1/#comment-2407</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 19:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=136#comment-2407</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hi Steevo. I&amp;apos;ll see if I can take a look at the version mismatch sometime this week. I&amp;apos;m guessing the file just wasn&amp;apos;t updated to reflect the new version number.

As far as working with the pics add on - the pics add on modifies the underlying HTML, making it difficult or impossible for the spam buttons script to find the HTML elements it needs to work with. At this point I have no plans to make it compatible with the pics add on.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi Steevo. I&apos;ll see if I can take a look at the version mismatch sometime this week. I&apos;m guessing the file just wasn&apos;t updated to reflect the new version number.</p>
<p>As far as working with the pics add on &#8211; the pics add on modifies the underlying HTML, making it difficult or impossible for the spam buttons script to find the HTML elements it needs to work with. At this point I have no plans to make it compatible with the pics add on.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Steevo		</title>
		<link>/craigslist-spam-buttons-v13/comment-page-1/#comment-2406</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steevo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 19:44:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=136#comment-2406</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Is anyone there? 

I am having some trouble with the craigslist flagging script.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Is anyone there? </p>
<p>I am having some trouble with the craigslist flagging script.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Steevo		</title>
		<link>/craigslist-spam-buttons-v13/comment-page-1/#comment-2362</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steevo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2011 22:08:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=136#comment-2362</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, it just gets more and more complicated. 

1. Ryan, your userscripts page says version 1.4 but the version there is 1.39. If there is actually a version 1.4 it has not been posted.&#160;&#160;Kind of a waste.&#160;&#160;So that should be corrected. 

2. I started using the CL Pics addon. That extension puts thumbnails of each picture inline in search results. It&amp;apos;s very helpful but it&amp;apos;s not usable with the spam buttons script running. If spam buttons is running all the pictures are duplicated, some up to 4x.&#160;&#160;It&amp;apos;s ridiculous. 

Can one of you smart guys do a little maintenance on this script?&#160;&#160;Thanks!]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, it just gets more and more complicated. </p>
<p>1. Ryan, your userscripts page says version 1.4 but the version there is 1.39. If there is actually a version 1.4 it has not been posted.&nbsp;&nbsp;Kind of a waste.&nbsp;&nbsp;So that should be corrected. </p>
<p>2. I started using the CL Pics addon. That extension puts thumbnails of each picture inline in search results. It&apos;s very helpful but it&apos;s not usable with the spam buttons script running. If spam buttons is running all the pictures are duplicated, some up to 4x.&nbsp;&nbsp;It&apos;s ridiculous. </p>
<p>Can one of you smart guys do a little maintenance on this script?&nbsp;&nbsp;Thanks!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Jay		</title>
		<link>/craigslist-spam-buttons-v13/comment-page-1/#comment-1647</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2010 10:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=136#comment-1647</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Is this site like Craigslist? lol.. I posted on here earlier asking for help and my post got flagged/deleted! I sell my products on CL and I have a competitor who keeps flagging me! My post gets removed within minutes and for some reason I can&amp;apos;t remove his post. Even after flagging his post using proxies and several ip&amp;apos;s hundreds of times it has no effect on his post! I need to know if someone knows how his ad is not removed but why mine comes down in minutes? Is there some type of anti flag code I can use to keep my ads up? Is there a way I can flag his ad and remove it? Someone please help me! I have a family to provide for and CL helps alot but I can&amp;apos;t even keep my ad up for 20 mins because he targets me and flags until my ad comes down! I&amp;apos;ll gladly pay someone top dollar for your help!!! Thank you!]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Is this site like Craigslist? lol.. I posted on here earlier asking for help and my post got flagged/deleted! I sell my products on CL and I have a competitor who keeps flagging me! My post gets removed within minutes and for some reason I can&apos;t remove his post. Even after flagging his post using proxies and several ip&apos;s hundreds of times it has no effect on his post! I need to know if someone knows how his ad is not removed but why mine comes down in minutes? Is there some type of anti flag code I can use to keep my ads up? Is there a way I can flag his ad and remove it? Someone please help me! I have a family to provide for and CL helps alot but I can&apos;t even keep my ad up for 20 mins because he targets me and flags until my ad comes down! I&apos;ll gladly pay someone top dollar for your help!!! Thank you!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Steevo		</title>
		<link>/craigslist-spam-buttons-v13/comment-page-1/#comment-1642</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steevo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2010 17:54:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=136#comment-1642</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&amp;apos;s working. 

As to pages with nearby results, I haven&amp;apos;t seen freezing but I the link opens the wrong area.&#160;&#160;The script doesn&amp;apos;t allow for those out of area results so tries to flag in the area denoted in the page url.&#160;&#160;

Which for the nearby results is wrong. That could probably be fixed but it hasn&amp;apos;t been.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&apos;s working. </p>
<p>As to pages with nearby results, I haven&apos;t seen freezing but I the link opens the wrong area.&nbsp;&nbsp;The script doesn&apos;t allow for those out of area results so tries to flag in the area denoted in the page url.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>Which for the nearby results is wrong. That could probably be fixed but it hasn&apos;t been.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
