<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Craigslist spam buttons script updated	</title>
	<atom:link href="/greasemonkey-craigslist-spam/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/greasemonkey-craigslist-spam/</link>
	<description>Web development notes and commentary from Ryan Stille</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2010 00:30:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Flagger		</title>
		<link>/greasemonkey-craigslist-spam/comment-page-2/#comment-1176</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Flagger]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2010 00:28:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2007/11/08/greasemonkey-craigslist-spam/#comment-1176</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I still don&amp;apos;t believe you Janet, think you&amp;apos;re full of it.&#160;&#160;It won&amp;apos;t let me post links here so how about an email address?&#160;&#160;I&amp;apos;ll send you a few ad links and see if you can flag them off.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I still don&apos;t believe you Janet, think you&apos;re full of it.&nbsp;&nbsp;It won&apos;t let me post links here so how about an email address?&nbsp;&nbsp;I&apos;ll send you a few ad links and see if you can flag them off.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Joeker		</title>
		<link>/greasemonkey-craigslist-spam/comment-page-2/#comment-1171</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joeker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2010 14:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2007/11/08/greasemonkey-craigslist-spam/#comment-1171</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One question - Are you posting legally (ie. by the Craigslist Terms of Use http://www.craigslist.org/about/terms.of.use )?&#160;&#160;

&#160;&#160; I&amp;apos;ve not seen people (competitors or not) flag posts that are not over-posted (multi-posts or multi-areas), prohibited, or in the wrong category (if you provide a service it belongs in services!).

&#160;&#160; Nobody should be flagging their competitors unless they&amp;apos;re breaking the ToU.&#160;&#160;If they do, they shouldn&amp;apos;t be unhappy when CL kicks ALL businesses off!
Joe]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One question &#8211; Are you posting legally (ie. by the Craigslist Terms of Use <a href="http://www.craigslist.org/about/terms.of.use" rel="nofollow ugc">http://www.craigslist.org/about/terms.of.use</a> )?&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp; I&apos;ve not seen people (competitors or not) flag posts that are not over-posted (multi-posts or multi-areas), prohibited, or in the wrong category (if you provide a service it belongs in services!).</p>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp; Nobody should be flagging their competitors unless they&apos;re breaking the ToU.&nbsp;&nbsp;If they do, they shouldn&apos;t be unhappy when CL kicks ALL businesses off!<br />
Joe</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Betty		</title>
		<link>/greasemonkey-craigslist-spam/comment-page-2/#comment-1170</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Betty]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2010 12:13:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2007/11/08/greasemonkey-craigslist-spam/#comment-1170</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have a small business and a few days ago some guy by the name of the craigslist flagger started harassing me via E-mail telling me that he watches every ad that I post and he is going to Flagg me if I continue to post. I’m 100% sure its a competitor. Every time I post an ad, 5 minutes later it gets flag. The worst part is that this guy sends me tex messages threatening me telling me that some thing is going to happen to me if I continue to post. 
I file a police report and the police told me they can’t really do nothing unless something happens to me. This monster goes by the name of the craigslist flagger using this email address CraigsList Master Flagger apr@socal.rr.com
This is the number he uses wo tex me some very nasty emails. 818-854-0743

I also file a report with Craig’s list and I havent got a reply from them yet.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have a small business and a few days ago some guy by the name of the craigslist flagger started harassing me via E-mail telling me that he watches every ad that I post and he is going to Flagg me if I continue to post. I’m 100% sure its a competitor. Every time I post an ad, 5 minutes later it gets flag. The worst part is that this guy sends me tex messages threatening me telling me that some thing is going to happen to me if I continue to post.<br />
I file a police report and the police told me they can’t really do nothing unless something happens to me. This monster goes by the name of the craigslist flagger using this email address CraigsList Master Flagger <a href="mailto:apr@socal.rr.com">apr@socal.rr.com</a><br />
This is the number he uses wo tex me some very nasty emails. 818-854-0743</p>
<p>I also file a report with Craig’s list and I havent got a reply from them yet.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Janet		</title>
		<link>/greasemonkey-craigslist-spam/comment-page-2/#comment-1168</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2010 16:39:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2007/11/08/greasemonkey-craigslist-spam/#comment-1168</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Is that right? Let&amp;apos;s test my program shall we. Forward me a couple of your ad links and we&amp;apos;ll is if they come down or not.&#160;&#160;; )]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Is that right? Let&apos;s test my program shall we. Forward me a couple of your ad links and we&apos;ll is if they come down or not.&nbsp;&nbsp;; )</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Flagger		</title>
		<link>/greasemonkey-craigslist-spam/comment-page-2/#comment-1165</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Flagger]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2010 03:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2007/11/08/greasemonkey-craigslist-spam/#comment-1165</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Janet, you&amp;apos;re full of it.&#160;&#160;No program is working now that flags ads automatically.&#160;&#160;Also, effective Oct. 2009, Craigslist made the flagging system only work on flags where the IP addres was local to the ad.&#160;&#160;This killed the Craigsflagger program and all others.&#160;&#160;The only way to effectively flag ads now is to drive around and hit wireless hotspots.&#160;&#160;I do this often to fight back against my competition.&#160;&#160;I have a string of wireless locations lined out.&#160;&#160;I can flag anything off at will if I want to take the time.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Janet, you&apos;re full of it.&nbsp;&nbsp;No program is working now that flags ads automatically.&nbsp;&nbsp;Also, effective Oct. 2009, Craigslist made the flagging system only work on flags where the IP addres was local to the ad.&nbsp;&nbsp;This killed the Craigsflagger program and all others.&nbsp;&nbsp;The only way to effectively flag ads now is to drive around and hit wireless hotspots.&nbsp;&nbsp;I do this often to fight back against my competition.&nbsp;&nbsp;I have a string of wireless locations lined out.&nbsp;&nbsp;I can flag anything off at will if I want to take the time.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Janet		</title>
		<link>/greasemonkey-craigslist-spam/comment-page-2/#comment-1117</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2010 05:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2007/11/08/greasemonkey-craigslist-spam/#comment-1117</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&amp;apos;m a small company that has been posting on CL for quite some time than all of a sudden my ads started getting flagged left and right by my competitor. I tried to reason with my competitor but they would not listen.&#160;&#160;I decided to make a program that would flag their multiple ads the put up on a daily basis.&#160;&#160;I contacted them and told them what I was going to do but they continued to flag my ads. I started flagging all there ads and guess what? They stopped flaggin my ads.&#160;&#160;I guess from time to time you need to fight fir with fire!&#160;&#160;it worked for me : )&#160;&#160;

clspamkiller1@gmail.com]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&apos;m a small company that has been posting on CL for quite some time than all of a sudden my ads started getting flagged left and right by my competitor. I tried to reason with my competitor but they would not listen.&nbsp;&nbsp;I decided to make a program that would flag their multiple ads the put up on a daily basis.&nbsp;&nbsp;I contacted them and told them what I was going to do but they continued to flag my ads. I started flagging all there ads and guess what? They stopped flaggin my ads.&nbsp;&nbsp;I guess from time to time you need to fight fir with fire!&nbsp;&nbsp;it worked for me : )&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="mailto:clspamkiller1@gmail.com">clspamkiller1@gmail.com</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Joeker		</title>
		<link>/greasemonkey-craigslist-spam/comment-page-2/#comment-1116</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joeker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2010 05:48:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2007/11/08/greasemonkey-craigslist-spam/#comment-1116</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There is no good way for 1 person to FLAG someone&amp;apos;s ads.&#160;&#160;It takes several different IP&amp;apos;s (people) to FLAG an ad.&#160;&#160;I&amp;apos;ve seen a number of businesses say &#034;I&amp;apos;m not breaking the rules&#034; yet next day they post similar ads in 3 categories in 2 different locations.&#160;&#160;I especially like the ones that add characters to the subject line yet claim they&amp;apos;re doing no wrong.

&#160;&#160; It&amp;apos;d be better if all businesses had to pay for CL ads!&#160;&#160;That&amp;apos;d cut down on the over-posting and violations significantly!&#160;&#160;Better yet - how &amp;apos;bout no business ads at all?&#160;&#160;Or move all business posting to a different section.

&#160;&#160; I&amp;apos;ve not seen any business which is following CL&amp;apos;s Terms of Use (which they all agree to when they sign up) get flagged within minutes of posting.

Joe]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There is no good way for 1 person to FLAG someone&apos;s ads.&nbsp;&nbsp;It takes several different IP&apos;s (people) to FLAG an ad.&nbsp;&nbsp;I&apos;ve seen a number of businesses say &quot;I&apos;m not breaking the rules&quot; yet next day they post similar ads in 3 categories in 2 different locations.&nbsp;&nbsp;I especially like the ones that add characters to the subject line yet claim they&apos;re doing no wrong.</p>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp; It&apos;d be better if all businesses had to pay for CL ads!&nbsp;&nbsp;That&apos;d cut down on the over-posting and violations significantly!&nbsp;&nbsp;Better yet &#8211; how &apos;bout no business ads at all?&nbsp;&nbsp;Or move all business posting to a different section.</p>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp; I&apos;ve not seen any business which is following CL&apos;s Terms of Use (which they all agree to when they sign up) get flagged within minutes of posting.</p>
<p>Joe</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Cathy		</title>
		<link>/greasemonkey-craigslist-spam/comment-page-2/#comment-1115</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cathy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2010 03:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2007/11/08/greasemonkey-craigslist-spam/#comment-1115</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have exactly the same problem as Roxy. This is completely UNFAIR, personally I think that Craigslist staff should change their policies and do something about these UNFAIR practices. So business have several posting for their business. However if I want to post my ad only once it is being flagged with NO REASON, just because I can be a competitor. I will be seeking help with that!!!]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have exactly the same problem as Roxy. This is completely UNFAIR, personally I think that Craigslist staff should change their policies and do something about these UNFAIR practices. So business have several posting for their business. However if I want to post my ad only once it is being flagged with NO REASON, just because I can be a competitor. I will be seeking help with that!!!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Roxy		</title>
		<link>/greasemonkey-craigslist-spam/comment-page-2/#comment-1109</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Roxy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 20:40:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2007/11/08/greasemonkey-craigslist-spam/#comment-1109</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I think this is really unfair to people who are posting legitimate ads and having people use these programs to flag them down maliciously.&#160;&#160;I post ads for my business that fall in line 100% with craigslist rules, yet someone, perhaps a competitor flags my ads down within minutes.&#160;&#160;It&amp;apos;s just unfair.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I think this is really unfair to people who are posting legitimate ads and having people use these programs to flag them down maliciously.&nbsp;&nbsp;I post ads for my business that fall in line 100% with craigslist rules, yet someone, perhaps a competitor flags my ads down within minutes.&nbsp;&nbsp;It&apos;s just unfair.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Johnny		</title>
		<link>/greasemonkey-craigslist-spam/comment-page-2/#comment-1073</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Johnny]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 04:17:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2007/11/08/greasemonkey-craigslist-spam/#comment-1073</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[CL is a Cespool of spam and illegal activity. Its a clear sign that flagging doesn&amp;apos;t work. In the big cities there are hundreds of dealers without permits operating on craigslist. There is everything from drugs to prostitution and even child porn cd-roms and not to mention the regulars which is 10000 counterfeit DVD, Phones, Software, Clothes posted daily.. The utlimate flagging tool would be a DA that puts that loser craig away for a long time for facilitating all this illegal activity.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>CL is a Cespool of spam and illegal activity. Its a clear sign that flagging doesn&apos;t work. In the big cities there are hundreds of dealers without permits operating on craigslist. There is everything from drugs to prostitution and even child porn cd-roms and not to mention the regulars which is 10000 counterfeit DVD, Phones, Software, Clothes posted daily.. The utlimate flagging tool would be a DA that puts that loser craig away for a long time for facilitating all this illegal activity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
